Written on 6/9/2025 Malaysia Time
=================================

HORRIBLE AIRPORT TOUR
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

4th September 2025 - 5th September 2025

==============================================

PREFACE

As I was staying here circulting around Putrajaya and Cyberjaya for around 2 weeks, if I can recall it correctly, I need to start another move. As I decided to move again to the airport living for around 7 days, a previous alarm triggered during my last time in the airport area had started to fade out -- it alarmed me that I might need longer time before I could go back to the airport, to prevent from being identified by mainly the staff which may then lead to a situation of me for being checked my identity that would subsequently cause adverse effects. Maybe because I assumed this time would be fine, I started my journey on 4th of September and was finally arrived in the airport area that night, or probably, that night on the next day.

I picked up a Touch 'n Go card, a contactless, electronic card which can be used across Malaysia's transportation services, and approached Putrajaya Sentral. As I'm unsure about the usage of the card, to prevent troubles if card stops working when I will be leaving the station in front of the barrier gate, I asked the staff for confirmation whether or not it can be used as it had around RM24 -- I said the exact amount from the machine which can check balance. The staff confirmed that I can use, then I left the station for urination, but when I approached back, the woman who stayed near the barrier gate asked me to wait -- possibly she was going to do further checks? I had no idea, but I knew that it must not be calling police to check my identity! I waited and saw she entered the counter area, rather than walking straight to the working seat, she entered another door inside the area dividing the exteriors with the counter. A man later appeared, refusing me to take the train because of my "smelling" -- I knew he refered to my odors, as I had not been washed my body for around or more than 2 weeks. I had no way but to leave the station, with initially full of disgusting as thinking of discriminations, that they must should allow those people exhibiting more annoying smellings, for example those of cigarette smoke, to embark the train; later on the way walking to the airport, my throught changed the tone, with full understanding of their decision -- no matter what did they do to others, the individual case to refuse me board the train is plausible, as no people wants those bad odor to appear in the cabin. Overall, KLIA Ekspres' train service gave me more than expected excellent experience, and I should not ruin the satisfications of other passengers.

Following the directions of the road signs, around national highway E6, I headed to the airport for another time. Before then, I bought 2 bottles of 7 Up of 1.5 liters and drunk them all at a time, this time I need to see if 3 liters is enough throughout the trip.

I. DURING THE TRIP

I walked along the highway to the direction to the Kuala Lumpur International Airport. For the first 2-3 hours, I was signing while seeing the running of the road system -- as well as experiencing the immersed scene of me making progress during the move. I'm really an experience walker, and I can even follow the correct lane designed for use of motorised vehicles with the direction of the road signs. Being prould of a safe walker with a record of walking since the first time alone on the road for at least 8 years, each move including walking along the service way, stopping for cars to pass until safe to cross the road, changing lanes for correct direction... I can be delighted for just experiencing a single action on the road -- I know this is what I'm capable of.

This time of trip, until the very near end I did not feel thirsty -- around half of route I felt like I just wanted to drink water, but no feeding was okay. As I started to get the sense of anticipating water, it was near end and shortly, possibly around 40-80 minutes after I started to feel a sight thirst I arrived in the McDonald's restautrant near the airport region, McDonald's Petronas KLIA DT.

After asking for free water and ordered something to eat, I started again to approach the airport. This restaurant always gives me plain water, as they collect it at my request into the bottle I give to them from the McCafe faucet mainly used for food procssing of McCafe drinks -- I get the high quality of water at no cost just by visiting and asking. With much of thanks to the staff, after eating well I headed to Terminal 1, especially to an open space near the parting lot buildings where I used to sleep in the darkness on the stairs. I love places like those where I could sleep at a relatively safe and startled place without being easily noticed by others nearby.

The first night was peaceful, bowever dramatic change started not even a bit of late on the second day.

II. THE START OF TROUBLES AND CONFRONTATIONS

As I woke up on the next day, 5th September, I really felt sleppy and wanted to continue my sleep for around 8 hours cumulative as I thought it must not be 7 hours which I need to avoid to ensure health body development. However that place was no longer startled once the sun enshrines it, so I need to find another place, not to be so startled since the sun could cover most places a brightness, but the most important thing is that, it must not be putting me vulnerable to animal attacks and it should avoid possible complaints from the public or being discovered by airport staff which could trigger further actions.

Finding that place would be hard as my maanifest may tells others an image of homelessness. My T-shirt had not been washed for weeks long and with previous stays under an escalated bridge dusts had made this originally moderate-dark-green-looking suits nearlly black; however, I insisted that sleeping is even more important and I proceeded to find a grass field which I believe was safe from animals. Tangent has made it less comfortable but as long as it was not too vertical, I could address it well. I slept for a short time, then proceeded to the nearby underground of an escalated bridge as the sunshine became intense, making me felt hot.

The sleep was fine, but shortly after waking up, troubles started. Shortly after I was about to leave the place, 2 vehicles, one followed by another, drove by and stopped near me. As I moved to ensure safety, people inside assured me that they shouldn't be for catching me, but the purpose remained unclear. Later, people from the leap vehicle gave me 2 packs of breads with one speaking Chinese asking me something, and another vehicle, with its look being imppressed me the most, embodied a Malaysia Airports logo with staff speaking English asking me my originating country and the time I arrived in this sleeping place. Previous experiences quickly know me that I was discovered byy someone and they were treating me as homeless people. I did not respond to the Chinese-speaking man with Chinese and indeed, did not tell the English-speaking person my originating country, but just saying that I moved here that morning.

The previous vehicle left quickly, but the latter one did not refrain. Thinking of incidents that had ever happened in the airport, for example the assassination of the North Korean in Terminal 2, and about the concrete needs of the airport to ensure safety, I knew that they must not refrain having seeing my appearance and they may need to report this to police, and possibly, the agency I mostly intended to avoid, the immigration department. While I may not be discovered to have overstayed in Malaysia at the scene if the officers check my identity, they may later key in the details to their computers and if I was discovered later even when I have escaped to safety, I would become sterile to visiting the airport in a slightly long time period -- if I am discovered by someone who knows me at a later time, I would face severe difficulties, if he/she decides to push me into this situation.

I explicitly asked if I could walk into the terminal as I told them that I wish to contact the airlines at 1pm, a lie, of course. They said that I could get to the terminal and that "they [staff in the terminal] may help me." This raised my suspisioas they might be calling authorities thereafter, identifing me and resulting in an identity check, most likely, however I'm unsure of the likelihood of them calling those authorities. I planned to walk into the terminal and before finally reaching it, observe the scenes near the entrance to see if it was safe to go in. As I started walking, that car quickly disappeared without me even noticed its trail. I knew that they're not some good people, not because they may intentionally harm me, but because of their conducts just now and considering about the current development progress of Malaysia's society some impolite and possibly offensive behaviours may also appear from time to time. They already disgusted me -- a man silently positioned his smartphone camera towards me, of surely I know he was capturing me for sending to his manager, which would be eventually sent to the command center of the airport if it has one -- but after all it was me who first exhibitted inappropriate behaviour which triggered further actions of the airport. Even if they were pursuing their duty, safety still cannot be guaranteed especially if theyy considered me a security threat, so I must be careful.

A little happening allowed me to know that they were tracing me -- as I turned my body to watch a bird apparently trying to eat a dead body of animal on the road, I suddenly noticed their vehicle were driving slowly following me behind. I decided to walk back and leave the airport area fast.

As I was walking towards the exiting direction of the road, they did not refrain. I stopped by after a distance and tried to observe the car flow, the Malaysia Airports vehicle of the same kind, and I even believe that was exactly the one I had confronted, because the blocs placed on the back of it were clarly visible with identical layout of placement. I witnessed possibly dozens of that car running past me before it disappeared and another suspision was noticed. A man, riding a motorcycle on the road I remembered to be connecting branches heading to the arrivals and departures hall, wearing a vest with vibrant colour believed to be designed for some service purposes, but carrying a backpack. Initially his wearing had drawed immediate attention -- I didn't seem to witness motorcycles on the same road in the past as I've ever walked on it for many times, well there might be motorcycles but his wearing was a big suspision -- he might be a staff of the airport, wishing to use his backpack to conceal this fact but working rules prevented him from taking this prominent vest off while working. As my mind was sill on this scene, 2 motocyclists riding motocycles bearing red MP letters emerged into my sight. Of course I know these stand for Military Police -- I witnessed cars bearing both the MP letters and the Military Police script while walking in Putrajaya as National Day parade was approaching -- those "friendly" cars had told me everything about the role of what they were designed to be used for. This furtherly affirmed my suspicion.

I continued to walking for leaving the area considered as premises of the airport. As I was walking along the road almost exiting the area I believed to be managed by the airport, the alarm from a car told me that it was jusst behind me. The Malaysia Airports car, possibly a new one or the same one, with same or similar design, went behind me. The man driving the car, possiby the team's lead, asked me again if I was Malaysian or not -- during initial confrontation I showed someone asking me questions payment cards from my wallet, and I especially flipping my Maybank card as most Malaysians have out to let him see it -- on the one hand this can assure them that I'm not a vagrant, on the other hand this could make them thinking of me a possibly Malaysian. Initially after I showed that Maybank card the man immediately asked me if I was Malaysian, and this time the same question went out. The card made good use of disguising rather than to providing me with banking services, while I was yet to finally compell the bank to issuing me a debit card, this card I captured while walking long-distance along the motorised lane made a special use during that moments. I still remember that I captured it while walking on a road designed for motorised vehicles only which I suspect of an accidental drop while someone was driving fast on a motorcycle and he was unaware of it.

I do not remember if I was thinking of whether or not the card deterred the airport staff for calling immigration officials, but surely it had disguised me which might became a vital factor to my eventual successful escape. As I proceeded to walking past the round way which allows exiting vehicles to approaching the airport again by climbing this escalated bridge, and for which I consider walking past the airport managed area, I no longer saw any vehicles I could idenfity to be servicing the airport purposes -- those airport shutter bus and vehicles bearing the airport's logo or elements no longer appeared beyond this point. I felt that the airport staff had refrained from tracing me mainly because of this jurisdiction mandates for which they were trained to obey, but rather circulating the area to block my future possible entries and to inform relevant authorities if necessary. Feeling that no longer being traced, I proceeded to a nearby McDonald's restaurant, designed mainly for passengers of passing motorised vehicles, and ordered something for eating. My first meal of day happened after the stimulating confrontation with the airport and I had to eat rice with sauce which are sold at regular price throughout many or all McDonald's outlets in Malaysia in order to save money.

III. AFTER THE CONFRONTATION

When I was leaving the restaurant the rain had almost stopped. I walked into an open area, of course outside the airport area I had considered to be, and started a new round of deep thinking. I knew that continuing my 7-day plan at the airport became no longer viable, however after assessments of risk factors I decided to take the train back to Putrajaya. I decided to risk myself rather than risk the attacks of sleeping outside the desired areas as I did not find any areas considered safe. I decided to wait until nightmare arrives.

As night comes and the sky becomes dark, I walked again to the airport, but this time, not Terminal 1 but Terminal 2. I knew that there should be different managements despite may being under oversight of a same, broader management department, which would result in certain degree of fragementation of workforce, so that going to Terminal 2 would be less likely to trigger notices of people monitoring the scene CCTV throughout the premise. Unluckily I saw another Malaysia Airports vehicle of the same type, but this time it exhibited no suspicions but rather like a passing by. I proceeded to the other end of the rounding way to turn to the other direction heading to the roads to terminals, and later, I proceeded by approaching Terminal 2.

During the rest part walking on the road, I was so sensitive to nearby vehicles as I proactively looked to find any signs of 