Declaration on Ethical Quality Control Matters
For Electronic Documents of the ASYLUM-SEEKING-JOURNALS Git Repository
================================================

I hereby declare that each of the electronic documents of the "asylum-seeking-journals" Git repository were composed, constructed, and made in the full English knowledge of me. No any forms of external assistance including translation of any forms, assistance on usage of grammar of any forms, assistance on meanings of words of any forms, were given or being delibrately searched on my own.

However, basic spelling check may be used to ensure correctness of documents.

This means that each complete document were made with totally my own knowledge of (professional) English use. However, this mandate does not preclude any activities of receiving assistance that happens during the breaks between different explicitly made Git commits, as there are still many English words on some subjects of usage yet to be learned, for example, people's emotions and feelings; some scientific subjects such as physics, chemistry, biology, etc.; and other subjects such as legislation and international laws and their related.

Additionally, language use of Git commit messages and filename edits, are also included within the mandate of such quality control measures. This means that a whole process of composing a Git commit message is also subjected to such quality control requirements, being considered as a single document edit.