Written on 4/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Exploring New Locations
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

2nd October 2025 - 4th October 2025

===================================

PREFACE

Despite I found the sanctuary of a McDonald's outlet was still consider a sanctuary, that is, it provides a section with high tables and charging sockets available for plugging in electronic devicess underneath where the location avoids visible video cameras as I checked multiple times before, so that I can keep a posture relatively confortable to me, standing while using the plugged in devices while also accessing the Internet with their WiFi, without the worries of a hidden eye looking at my behaviour which would then trigger a motivation of a removal from the staffers, I still need to cherish this opportunity by not coming to it too frequently -- my visit and leaving would become noticable. So that, I started to exploring a new place again, while I also would love to finding a better place for sleeping without the need of a tent.

I embarked on the MRT train at the Hospital Kuala Lumpur station and debarked at the 16 Sierra station. Previous studies revealed that this location is relatively new, so I guess it might be less populated and have less overhead electricity cables which I would easily to avoid for safety reasons.

Another clothes washing finished before I was going to leave the station. The water was again black being rendered by the dirts of the clothes -- it was only around a week and both my T-shirt and the shorts was able to making the water becoming heavy gray to true black.

I. AFTER EXITING THE STATION

After leaving the interior area of the station, I was being presented scene of yet-to-be-developed lands. I followed the steps of other people, entered a carpark area with aggregated water on the ground, but was later found that it was just a carpark, so I turned to another way. It was a long walk compared with most metro stations until I could find real commercial areas with merchant outlets -- the station was surrounded by buildings looked like for residential use. I was wondering what this place was.

Later when I was walking to a McDonald's outlet I realised that the name "16 Sierra" was actually used by a commercial development! The electronic maps also confirmed that despite it's not dense, it's also lessly developed. I began walking towards the park in Cyberjaya where I used to sleeping as night has approached. I estimated that 2 hours would be exhausted until arrival, but I need to sleep first before exploring other places.

II. FOUND A GOOD SANCTUARY IN A SUDDEN

When I was about to setting up a tent for sleeping as I did not want to move anymore, I decided to move on for better safety. Within just no more than a kilometre, or even more closer, I found an escalated bridge supplying with radius-shaped concrete for which it makes a platform. It requires modest hardship to me to log on to. It was night, and judging by the manifest of the logged on area it should be very obscure despite there might have been someone ever visited before. I roughly checked the area, and chose a place I consider safe from intruders, and went to sleep. No tents were used.

I went into sleep shortly.

III. A WHOLE DAY ON THE PLATFORM

I spent a whole day, on 3rd September 2025, on the platform. While I was about to move on, the weather condition worried me; while I was considering to buying foods at the nearby McDonald's, money I spent on a previous day stopped me from proceeding. Especially, on the previous day I went to that McDonald's to buy foods not only for eating, but also to collect a copy of receipt for collection purposes, with other purposes related to card payment matters, which made me spent more so that I need to cut spending on the next day for moderation.

I was using Internet in the morning, and in the afternoon the laptop battery got exhausted so I must shut down before it shuts down for me, as this would cause the system clock to have problems. I went into deep thinking thereafter.

When night comes, I went into sleep early. This time I moved to a place considered more safere as I found that another side allows relatively easier climbing to reach this platform on the 2nd day.

During daytime, I also climbed the radius to the even higher place. I found newspapers and a Foodpanda poster, these objects suggested that somebody had come here in recent months. These different newspapers in English and Malay are dated back in July 2025, and the poster also suggested that it was from the recent years.

IV. READY TO GO

On 4th September, the weaather condition allowed me to move on. I first bought meals from that McDonald's again, and then went back to the sanctuary for short rest before proceeding to Cyberjaya. I plan to buy clothes and shoes first before moving forward.

It was so hot outside, and I was almost instantly felt about the hot after walking out of the bridge. On my way back, I realised that with my tent and sleeping bag being carried it slowed me down my steps so prominently, as I took around 30-40 minutes until arrival. I slept again during daytime at this place, but I no longer remember if it was after McDonald's or before when I'm writing this journal. After taking a rest, I knew it's time to proceed to the next destination -- "life needs to be continued," I told myself this phrase in Chinese in my mind. Stepping out of the platform, I went on for Cyberjaya and arrived at night. Bought something for imminent eating and for future days, I went on to the nearby park for sleeping.