Written on 3/11/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Being Prone to Fraud is Persistent Issue for Mobile Operators
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

2 November 2025

===================================

DETAILS OF INCIDENT

I went to a service center of a Malaysia mobile service operator, as my SIM card was accidentically locked requiring a PUK code to unblock. As I approached the outlet and was initially waiting for my queue number be called, I realise that they may be able to check this information directly without me having to wait for long. I expressed my intention of needing to get the PUK, and a staaff recorded my phone number and appraoched a desk counter possibly asking for a check.

Surprisingly, when he came back to me, a photo of computer screen displaying the operator's BSS system, a system used to manage customer relationships and business process serving for customers, which shows the PUK code with other subscriber information, was presented in front of my eyes. I was very surprised that they did not even ask for my passport for verification as I thought they might not be knowing me since I don't often come to their service centers, and even if they know, what the staff behaved doesn't seem to be knowing me personally. I knew that SIM card swapping is a well-known fraud and this is widespread even in developed Western countries, but that day of experience still surprised me as even protrayed procedure was not initiated.

That helpful staff, a man having look as Chinese race with a light skin colour, presented a total of 2 images in front of me, which include the service number of subscriber, internal classification of service type of subscription of the operator, suspension date of subscription (in case of dormancy), the mobile number porting status which is displayed as completed porting in, the 2nd Personal Unblock Key (PUK) of the SIM card, the PUK1, the mobile service plan, IMSI of the SIM profile, registration date of subscriber, calculated tenure of tenancy (subscription), and more. The BSS screen being captured, also included my another phone number listed as service number as that one is also registered on my same identity document! So yes, basic particulars of my service is no longer considered a privacy as these are necessary for service personnel to diagnose possible issues if customers approach their office, but most importantly, these information can drive targeted promotions by the staff to make the company generate revenue, so of course the company is indeed getting in love with money, along with so many numbers of commercial companies, individuals, and even some for-profit organisations registered them as NGOs. And, of course, I'm also included on the list.

I requested him to send an original copy of these 2 images on my WhatsApp number, and he absolutely did without asking for further verification of my identity. Then I also used my tablet to capture the images displayed on his phone's screen.

OUTCOME

This gives me a relative clearer overview of the hierarchy of different modules being designed into this BSS system, which serves as an important information source for my studies on this operator as well as how cellular operators in Malaysia design and use their IT systems to view and amend information of mobile subscriptions as well as to manipulate services of subscribers on request or in case of need.

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

To the details of this operator involved in this incident, I refuse to disclose as this not only gains disproprionate disadvantages to the operator but also may endanger my asylum seeking journey in Malaysia. The same issue happens not only on this operator but on many around the globe, from developing countries to even highly developed states, and that the nature of this problem is due to many factors of the industry, therefore this operator should not be held responsible full of their mistakes.

It should also be noted that my asylum seeking journey should not be affected by operator staff for extracting detailed usage data including the appropriate location of my mobile devices used to access the network, as such information by nature is not visible to the BSS interface facing regular customer service processes but is only accessible to a small fraction of people within the company, so that there's nothing to worry about beyond exercising normal precautions under my existing security defense framework during everyday use. Massive and arbitrary extractions of those sensitive data including location and call logs, do only exist in some less developed countries and those dictatorships such as Vietnam, Thailand and China, and therefore Malaysia is absolutely not subject to this issue.