Written on 20/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

CITIC Bank's Sudden Change
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

This event happened someday during the second half of 2025.

===================================

I. Background Information

Maybe it was back in the time when I was still living in my China's house, I noticed that even with all the required browser add-ons installed as stipulated on their downloads page which aggregates an array of middleware of USB security tokens and a component used to provide inputs of passwords being as a required component prescribed by the Central Bank (PBOC), the sign-in page still disallow user actions of performing online banking sign-ins with a message to download their "E-banking Companion" (in Chinese, Wangyin Banlv). In addition to this, during the time I was in Shenzhen earlier this year, I failed to log on to the user portal despite entering correct username (ID card number or debit card number) and password and with everything required installed, on those terminals of the branch serving for customers' use, as a WeChat Mini Program 2D barcode subsequently showed following each time of sign-in attempt requiring a scanning of the code on a WeChat mobile application and having the customer's face captured and recorded by the application, for the purported verifcation purposes.

A bank staff did helped me with a time of scanning, with me writing a statement and affixed on my face for the section of recording a video speaking numbers displayed in sequence as required. It was confirmed on different computer terminals from the branches that this no longer required subsequently, but was later reinstated for some unknown reason. From that time on, I had never completed such a section again.

II. A Sudden Finding!

Someday while I was in Malaysia accessing the Internet with my laptop, I decided to give it a try again. I knew that China's policy is so volatile so are the policies of their agencies, so I might get a different and possibly surprising outcome, but I knew this doesn't come with guarantee.

With add-ons installed but not running any of their E-banking Companion installers, I suddenly noticed that no "big blocs" were on display! I went on and entered my username (possibly ID card number this time) and password, and finally, I was logged on to the portal! Despite the fact, as remembered, that only partial contents were loaded, but I knew it was not the page asking for WeChat scanning based on limited information on display, the menu which allows navigating around different e-banking sections.

After subsequent refreshes, I was provided with a portal UI with functionalities I can use, such as checking balance etc.

I suspected that it was because Internet from outside China was detected, but I was unsure.

III. Post Event Details

After this event, I contacted bank's customer service hotline and nothing, either an answer to if the bank's policy had changed or if sign-in was happened outside China, had confirmed, on the matter of no longer requiring WeChat for account sign-ins. Additionally, the staff only gave apparent in-principal response which they will narrate to all kinds of similar questions, followed by being asked why the E-banking Companion was no longer reqiored.

IV. Other Notable Details

It is previously learned, as I tried to install the E-banking Companion on an isolated virtual machine, that the software provides a one-stop entry to installing all the required browser add-ons -- password input components and USB security token middleware -- without users' manual operations, however the UI also suggested it has the functionalities to automatically checking for updated versions from the remote server reegularly. An earlier conclusion, made while I was still living in my Chiinese house, suggested that it's most likely the software, by then, would collect an array of particulars of system hardware and software environments such as device model and OS version including the Windows model (Home, Professional SKU) and platform version (e.g. 9200.16384 for Windows 8 family) to remote locations.