Written on 20/9/2025 Malaysia Time
=================================

SUDDEN ENFORCEMENT APPEARANCE
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

19th September 2025

==============================================
Finished editing on 20/9/2025 Malaysia Time
==============================================

PREFACE

As I was arriving at a flat bench located in front of the KKDW building, which is a building I believe a government building for the rural development department as I looked up online before, located in an island where many government buildings are situlated, I took out my tablet and turned on my laptop as usual, preparing to first take a picture of a payment receipt from a purchase at a store, and after that I would start to access the Internet using the WiFi that looks like coming from this building. Why I was sticking to this network was because I previously found some uniqueness of it -- Internet was provided by a special organisation rather than those providing retail Internet access services to customers on basis of purchases, and the company named GITN had demonstrated high-quality Internet which motivated me to using it. Internet in Malaysia is not controlled by the government and government institutions as well as universities and private organisations can perform Internet exchange and set up Internet infrastructure without the government intenvention, for which I really felt appreciated to seeing such a good horizon.

Shortly after I took a picture to save the receipt well into my tablet, just after I had turned on the laptop, a car drove in front of me stopping on the side of the street. 2 men disembarked and straightly walked to approach me.

If I could successfully spend that night and move again to other places during daytime, I would never be thinking of a suspicious moments when I was charging my laptop at a nearby bus stop, I observed a woman wearing a strip with a card-like object attached to the ending before his throax, having traditional attire and exhibited a looking as a conservative person which sees less-seen undesired behaviours strange and maybe unacceptable. I observed she looking at me for a short while as I was disguising myself as using the laptop as usual, and shortly after her leave I stowed everything and quickly left the place. This happened one day before this incident, in the morning of the 18th of September, and the looking of her immediately recalled me of a confrontation happened a few months ago at a place near the McDonald's Putrajaya DT restaurant when I was demanded a leave from Putrajaya by a woman identifying herself as from the welfare department of the government.

No matter if I was being reported in a complaint, 

I. INITIAL CONFRONTATION

A man, which had just exhaled a socket of smoke possibly from e-cigarette, started to talk with me. As I felt disgusted about his behaviour, I did not give him respect and started to ignore his words, however as I realised that this might be unusual, despite blurry in my mind, I asked them for their identity. Someone, or probably both of them, told me that they came from police which gave significant credibility in my mind as their behaviour including the tone of language they used, and with that smoking man who immediately ceased smoking and hided the object in his hand which was suggested to be an e-cigarette device. Possibly in fairness of being deported back into China, my home country for which I fled, after being identified my identity, I was having strong imagniation of being first apprehended into custody and later being taken onto a chartered flight for my country which I don't wish to move back into. During that time, my bags placed on the bench was being taken to their car and later with further talks, another man told me that he was going to taking me to Cyberjaya, followed by what I told him that I could walk to this city if they demanded me for leaving.

During this time, I also saw one of them pointing a phone camera towards me, possibly to making records. This had suggested that someone must have complained about me which prompted their arrival to deal with the matter.

I refused to embark on the car. Despite later I quickly confirmed that they were most likely genuine staffers from the police or another government entity, to avoid air pollution of spent petrol I demanded leaving on my own. During this time period, the smoking man who became agreesive on the first instance, started to moving behind me for which I considered likely to restrain my body without my notice. I was also moving to keep a safe distance.

II. ESCALATION OF CONFRONTATION WHICH LED INTO SUCCESSFUL GRASPING

I asked multiple times to giving back my items and I will leave Putrajaya immediately, however they did not return anything. As I was deciding to leave and abandon all of the items, when I was moving away, that agreesive man quickly ran towards me and grasped one of my shoulders. I was not running despite saw him getting close mainly because with drakness since it was night, running fast to escaping chase was considered dangerous as I might fall into craters which would endanger my life; another several factors including that my earlier conclusion showed that despite being detained by police still doesn't automatically constitute a deportation and the existing legal framework allows certain reach from the UN refugee agency (the UNHCR), with other skills I learnt to furtherly confront with police officers I was also feeling that detention is not a complete darkness with high risks of being deported; and the presence of many United Nations agencies including the UNHCR, UNDP, UNICEF, etc. where they can operate and organise events publicly, gave me even strong confidence that I would less likely to face danger. I started to know about this country since the first time getting in contact with a Malaysian SIM card, during which time I learned that English use in Malaysia was very common with which this gave me an unbeatable confidence of Malaysia's relatively good government governance compared with its neighbors.

I was subsequently taken into this car by both people. Despite being locked they still confirmed that they were going to send me to Cyberjaya, which gave me some confidence that I would not be sent to the police station. I told them to open the car's windows and it stayed open half the degree, and none of them used violence to cause physical harms. Additionally, no slurs were given by both people and no smoking behaviours were discovered during the trip driving me to Cyberjaya.

III. ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

One of them, who exhibited harmony, asked if I was Malaysian or not. I said that if you show me your identity documents I will show him "all the documents", while not exposing anything about my nationality. No police documents were shown and I was not asked directly to produce identity documents throughout the happening.

The car they were using had the ability of making alarms and it had flashing lights of blue colour, but no marks or names of the Malaysian police force was seen on one side of it.

After disembarking from the car, the plate code WLQ4712 was observed and recorded.

The details should also be recorded that the force was being used while there were few to no people nearly the area of the scene.

IV. POST INCIDENT AFTERMATHS

They did not even asking me for any identity documents in my possession, and I was being sent to a road where the card had stopped. It was next to the shopping mall for which it had a bus station on another side of it where I used to plugging in my electronic devices and using them. After that they left while had also returned all of my items they had collected previously.

It should be noted that while they told me that I cannot stay, possibly over a long time period or living overnight, in Putrajaya, according to the words of one of them I could stay at any place wherever I want outside this region. From the latter's words, as being asked if I could stay in other places outside Putrajaya on a probe of his knowledges about handling homelessness outside this city, it sounds like they knew that enforcements against homeless people was weak or they are completely allowed straying on the streets, rather than deceiving me in the hope of me seeking other places for living outside the city or region he has responsibility.

I was also feeling thankful to the industralisation of the modern society, as I was exposed to a relatively acceptable amount of noticable spent petrol air throughout the happening, because without continued evolution of technology from people in more civilised countries, people like me living outside of those countries will inevitably be less likely to benefit from those technology advancements and the outpaced technology would only cause more harms to humans.

V. KNOWLEDGES LEARNED FROM THIS EXPERIENCE

The following knowledges were learned from this experience immediately after its happening on the same day:--

  1. It's preferred for police officers to peer with one more harmonic and one more agreesive during missions of enforcement actions by the Malaysian police, as well as by police forces of many countries, in order to ensure moderation of police activities which guarantees prompt actions while also ensuring human rights of the participants, especially those being applied enforcements.

  2. Malaysia's approach on dealing homeless people mainly forcuses on Putrajaya, while a majority of places are more tolerant to them. Dealing with them mainly include removals of the identified homeless people, but penalising them is less likely.

  3. My approach of choosing Malaysia as a place for continued living while not having legal status, with the purpose of waiting for UNHCR registration, is proven to be scientific and effective. On the one hand, Malaysia deals with illegal immigrants while on the other hand not consolidating powers of different government acencies ensures human rights of inhabitants. Additionally the current development progress makes Malaysia to although having a number of  problems to the continent of Asia, but the country is moving towards democratically and politically mature, making certain civil rights possible and expanding; as the economy and education is progressing positively basic infrastructure is also improving which gives me a relative safe place for living compared with nearby countries despite having longer time of UNHCR registration in this country.

Additionally, the following knowledges were learned:--

  1.  On 20/9/2025 while writing the journal I also realised that my approach of not disclosing my nationality gives me more opportunities of not being considered an illegal immigrant on a first instance when being dealt by government officials, for example on the matters of homelessness. The fact of my skin colour closing to native Malay ethnicites had also helped me to giving an imagination of a local people, despite having Chinese looking, which supplement the non-disclosure exercises of nationality, to deterring or suppressing many officials to considering me as a foreigner.

VI. AFTERMATHS

In addition to evaluating the positive effects of my approach on dealing with police officers I also realised that I must act to invigorate myself to finding new places actively when assessments conclude a necessary which must not be neglected. In addition to moving actively everyday, it's also of vital importance to not lingering in certain places frequently which will prompt recognition of me by other people, especially those likely to lodge complaints against me on any matters which would draw adverse effects on me.

Another notable thing is that, I was believing that my movements were already captured by CCTV cameras deployed throughout the island -- they were not dense, but facing to many places critical to public safety. The use of this type of car not embedding significant police elements is probably a result of knowing that I was cautious as I often turn my head around and look behind while walking outdoors, but this may also due to other reasons including the internal procedure governing the operations of missions.

Carrying many dirty bags is also a prominent feature of me which prompts quick identification from aggregation of people. I estimate that reducing the size of bags to those commonly seen be carried by ordinary people decreases the likelihoods of being quickly identified by overseers of CCTV cameras and it would result in more safe time periods of lingering in fixed places.
