Written on 4/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Exploring New Locations
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

2nd September 2025 - 4th September 2025

===================================

PREFACE

Despite I found the sanctuary of a McDonald's outlet was still consider a sanctuary, that is, it provides a section with high tables and charging sockets available for plugging in electronic devicess underneath where the location avoids visible video cameras as I checked multiple times before, so that I can keep a posture relatively confortable to me, standing while using the plugged in devices while also accessing the Internet with their WiFi, without the worries of a hidden eye looking at my behaviour which would then trigger a motivation of a removal from the staffers, I still need to cherish this opportunity by not coming to it too frequently -- my visit and leaving would become noticable. So that, I started to exploring a new place again, while I also would love to finding a better place for sleeping without the need of a tent.

I embarked on the MRT train at the Hospital Kuala Lumpur station and debarked at the 16 Sierra station. Previous studies revealed that this location is relatively new, so I guess it might be less populated and have less overhead electricity cables which I would easily to avoid for safety reasons.

Another clothes washing finished before I was going to leave the station. The water was again black being rendered by the dirts of the clothes -- it was only around a week and both my T-shirt and the shorts was able to making the water becoming heavy gray to true black.

I. AFTER EXITING THE STATION

After leaving the interior area of the station, I was being presented scene of yet-to-be-developed lands. I followed the steps of other people, entered a carpark area with aggregated water on the ground, but was later found that it was just a carpark, so I turned to another way. It was a long walk compared with most metro stations until I could find real commercial areas with merchant outlets -- the station was surrounded by buildings looked like for residential use. I was wondering what this place was.

Later when I was walking to a McDonald's outlet I realised that the name "16 Sierra" was actually used by a commercial development! The electronic maps also confirmed that despite it's not dense, it's also lessly developed. I began walking towards the park in Cyberjaya where I used to sleeping as night has approached. I estimated that 2 hours would be exhausted until arrival, but I need to sleep first before exploring other places.

II. FOUND A GOOD SANCTUARY IN A SUDDEN

When I was about to setting up a tent for sleeping as I did not want to move anymore, I decided to move on for better safety. Within just no more than a kilometer, or even more closer, I found an escalated bridge supplying with radiation-shaped concrete for which it makes a platform which requires modest hardship to me to log on to. 