Written on 31/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Learning while Seeking Asylum -- Penetrate Into the F&B Sector (30-31 Oct 2025)
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

31 October 2025

===================================

NOTICE

The request of condiments and ingredients at McDonald's restaurants in Malaysia always comes on a voluntary basis honouring McDonald's policies. This means that for item purchases that do not include complimentary condiments and ingredients, an approach of behaving restrained always applies, that is, if a claim is denied, I will acknowledge the fact of the restaurant policy and refrain immediately asking.

Any use of power supply in any McDonald's restaurant I had visited is based on customary facts that such service is de facto be provided by the restaurant in an illicit manner, and is in consideration of the practices of the headquarters McDonald's Corporation of the USA, of building their chain of restaurants a multi-purpose workspaace serving customers with minimal or reasonable amenities for their processing of office works, including paperworks and of those conducted online.

Maintaining a high degree of ethical conducts is always at the heart of me, and this includes every process no matter if dealing with allies or adversaries.

I. Preface

I had been a spectator, possibly a spy in view of some Chinese Communists, as I observe how restaurants are driven to be run in the Food and Beverages (F&B) sector. As I was living alone, it prompted me of buying foods for living, so that shortly after I entered a foreign country for the first time (which marks the official starting of homelessness) I visited a McDonald's outlet. Thoughout the journey, as I buy and look at my foods, or even sometimes while I was waiting in front of the pick-up counter, I observed many details during which time I learned many things behind of the scene of this sector.

I forgot which McDonald's was the first one I visited, but during my early days in Kuala Lumpur I visited many of this restaurant chain very frequently. I still remembered that I allowed me to spending relatively more money, despite it might not be worth to the value of purchased products, in order to explore this country and its related industries and as I learned more I will gradually cut spending to be eventually buying only foods at a reasonable price. So during these very early stages, I not only ordered burgers such as Filet 'O Fish and McChicken, but also bought so many times their porridges, Sundae and McFlurry ice creams.

Shortly after eating McDonald's for the first time, maybe still during my first visit of Malaysia, I initially developed an approach of not loosing money so much on McDonald's by requesting many sachets of ketchup while most customers, until now, do not even ask for ketchup for their meals even when this service is explicitly included in their types of order. So for me, that would be 5 more sachets of ketchup compared with ordinary people!

And for ice creams, my approach was similar, that was, by requesting creamersof those packed into very small packages. They were also made from non-animal origin according to the packaging, this means that they may be eliminating many costs on dairy origins. I also remembered that the packaging also mentions the content is made from plant origin, this means that the manufacturing cost must be significantly declined compared to those coming from animals such as cows! So over time, I raised alaim that simply requesting 5 or even 7 pieces of creamers is not suffice, but I cannot also request more at a time as the number comes prominently if I say it, so it will most likely end up with nothing entirely!

Of course, I cannot simply give money to McDonald's while they do not give me products and services to the value spent. Later, I started to ordering plain coconut rice individually and sometimes, added sauce for each of them priced at 1 Malaysian Ringgit, but occasionally I still ended up ordering their ice cream, especially the one a combination of 3 items priced at RM12. I firstly saw this offer during the Ramadan period in Malaysia as I thought it was because McDonald's needed to process those ingredients, so I ordered regularly thinking of it super value, plus asking for creamers each time when picking up. Eventually I requested 7 pieces as a norm and most of the time it was satisfied. After Ramadan, I remembered that this offer once went missing on their ordering machine for a short period of time, but it came back afterwards. I started to thinking if this offer also makes McDonald's earn a lot despite there weren't any combinations of only confectionary at this price to this volume, or at least I did not get noticed. I ended up also by not buying this either.

Especially when in the airport, I strictly restrain myself to ordering only fixed price items, which maybe only this plain coconut rice and the RM1 sauces, but when outside of the airport I still cannot control myself. During this time I still did not know what 99 Speedmart a chain of shops selling super value items, so I compared countless numbers of ties McDonald's foods with items sold in 7-Eleven and other stores which sell at higher price. The worries and comparation ran into repeated circles and during this time, I still sometimes order confectionary by sending money to McDonald's despite I often heavily use their resources such as water in the toilet and hand soap provided for guests' use, plus their electricity for charging all of my devices whenever possible. I knew that this must end and I must find a place to buy foods and drinks at valuable prices.

During the process searching for shops selling valuable items, I always knew that the price of foods and drinks for which I had bought was relatively high. I did questioned as Malaysia was still a developing economy and this comes inconsistent with the education level of citizens and the development of the country, but I ended up thinking as this was probably because Kuala Lumpur is the capital city. I later visited Putrajaya and Cyberjaya but still got basically same and similar prices, so I once even thought of it was because they are relatively newly developed urban areas. During this time, 7-Eleven visits significantly declined but I still occasionally visiting some others including KK Mart for getting snacks, and I always avoid buying water and drinks unless I can't control myself drinking sweetened water because they come at an unacceptable price.

I ended up meeting with 99 Speedmart around the time when overstaying happens, and now I'm confidence to say that valuable items coming with prices I was intially expected, are being sold in many 99 stores across Malaysia on daily basis! While I must have spent so much of disproportionate money on McDonald's, I had also discovered many details behind the scene of what customers can instantly get just after the placement of orders. In this regards, I'm still loosing much fewer money than many of the customers, but I have learned to restrain myself so that I can now control myself to only ordering plain coconut rice and select types of sauces at RM1 if I need to use my own money!

II. The Exploration Process, Findings, and Achievements

Throughout months of visits to McDonald's, I learned that the most hardworking group of people are those preparing and serving meals to customers. They need to bring thenselves ready for listening to different pitches of sounds made by different machines in the kitchen, and respond with appropriate actions in order to ensure always uptime of the restaurant. Those people are often underprivileged due to their degree of education and many factors, many of them just wish to earn a living. Compared with these people, I could say my homeless life can be full of meaningful and fruitful activities!

People are less willing to provide me, and of course other customers, ketchup sachets as the cost of procurement is much higher than chilli sauce. I used to see the ingredients listed on the packaging comparing chilli sauce and ketchup, while there are a number of artificial substances added into chilli sauce, ketchup is made with almost or exactly all the ingredients that can be found naturally, despite I can't understand every listed item due to my poor chemistry knowledge compared with industry experts. Most customers would be given 2-5 sachets of chilli sauce for which it doesn't even worth RM0.2 I believe. At a later time during a visit of an outlet in Putrajaya, a staff told me that ketchup is much more expensive than chilli.

In order to efffectively prepare meals for customers, they need to monitor the displays installed inside the restaurant to see a list of customer orders as well as listed items in these orders. Sometimes immediately followed by a successful order a special long beep will happen but sometimes it does not, so later I concluded that this may be triggered after a certain period of time of inactivity, while during peak hours staff would concentrate on doing other things without intruption of repeated ordering notification. I know that this sound is essentially like calling dormant workers to resume their work, which could be tough to those occupants.

Unlike the obscure KFC restaurants across Malaysia, McDonald's in Malaysia focus on providing services looking like they're on a premium level. Their staffers have name places which need to be worn on the throax, and there is also a special kind of uniform in the pink colour, I guess this is for use by select roles that they build relationships with guests, especially those having volume orders. Whenever staffers need to deliver meals to customers who use the Table Service, a service which allows ordered meal be automatically sent to desired tables on customers' own choice, they need to treat customers with respectful emotions just like how secretaries treat their bosses in China. Additionally, when guests walk staff need to let way for them until they had passed, and if guests are about to placing something into the trash receptacle staffers must press the door to opening it for customer use.

I observed a few times when employee went uncontrollable or they spark their pressure by throwing plates or other objects. Some waiters are in their 20s while others may ne older, but not exceeding 40 years. Especially when some younger boys approach me, they treated me as a friend but sometimes, asking me of my personal background.

I used to be thinking of Coca-Cola having a non-negotiable practice on standards, but McDonald's is even allowed to add ice cubes into these Coca-Cola-branded drinks. This may be a sign of the capitalism world that money sometimes goes beyond company's own belief, especially when compromising allows more earning. I consider this practice as a compromise of Coca-Cola's own standards as adding ice lowers concentration of other ingredients such as flouring and syrup, but they may have another set of standard for those kind of drinks; however one thing I can almost confirm is, as employees are allowed to add ice cubes they would also be given the flexibility to making less concentrated drinks not meeting official standards in order to save cost on ingredients.

For their WiFi service, this is a must to almost or actually every McDonald's restaurants in Malaysia. I believe that this is now considered a mandatory by the McDonald's global headquarters for most countries. WiFi hotspots installed in Malaysia are Cisco Meraki APs, which gives very high quality of WLAN service while also simultaneously it captures website visits and other private data sent from customers' devices. I once searched online and found that another McDonald's presence in an European country also equips the same technology, so judging the fact that Meraki is a prestigious device provider providing high quality of products, I guess a number of McDonald's presences worldwide are now using this technology which benefits the headquarters for analysing how customers use the Internet in everyday life and especially when in eateries like McDonald's. Interestingly, some private DNS providers as well as the Tor network was earlier confirmed blocked by McDonald;s WiFi in Malaysia, this suggests that the company doesn't want customers to cover their privacy behind their networks since the data is too valuable to be given a price for selling -- they would love to keep it a property of them, I believe.

Up until now, there is a few numbers of McDonald's who have actually "politely" refused my subsequent visits by refusing to provide ketchup on orders such as plain rice or sauces. They may be knowing that I think of getting ketchup a vital part of eating McDonald's so that of course, this became an efficient tool they can leverage.

With a rough estimation, for a McChicken burger they sell at around RM5-7, the franchiser the US headquarters would earn at least RM0.6 while others are divided by local franchisers and franchisees, and a small portion is used to support the salary of employees. This makes the workers the most vulnerable group of people as fewer people means fewer orders, which will inevitably draw fewer salaries to them. I was once be given a number of ketchup sachets, possibly over 20, followed by a request, and it subsequently made a staff I saw was having instable moods puting a large amount into my takeout bag. He might be sparking his anger as each time I come ketchup must be consumed faster.

A back side of McDonald's I observed at least spreading widely in Malaysia is that, while fried chicken must be discarded after a certain period of time from cooking, some expired parts were used to serve customers. They place cooked items onto different levels of oven-like containers, so that they know which level has new parts while which level has old ones. They often put expired ones first so they stay at the bottom, stacking with new parts staying on the top, so that customers would only notice irregularities until they almost finished eating. However I never observed significant issues on food safety, the worst situation I witnessed is that a staff put a dropped Apple Pie from the ground back into the container, but I believe this is an isolated event happened because of personal quality instead of a widespread fashion.

McDonald's is also good at making diversed occurance, so that they can assess performances of different restaurants, while also ensuring not loosing customers from unhappiness happened in a particular restaurant. For example, they allow certain discreationary decisions be made by the manager, so that some restaurants may serve water while others may not. Especially for me, the direct feeling I had as I suffer from being refused to provide ketchup is, I knew this is not a common practice so that I could simply move to another one for ketchup. I later quickly realised that this is the wisdom of the management which leverages the power of diversity and democracy to achieve customer satisfaction -- that's said, "We at McDonald's in Malaysia is a monetary-driven company, however we do not directly tell it. We put procuring ketchup a responsibility on the restaurant level, so that they can decide if they will give you more or not; and if they do not, another one may do. We do not make explicit statement that we're money driven, but you must be thinking that refuse to give you ketchup is an isolated event which shouldn't happen in other restaurants, because it takes time for you to asking frequently in every restaurant making every people unhappy."

Another wisdom is their approach of making satisfying taste while driving additional sales afterwards. For example their fried chicken is high in protein and sodium, and as they sell 3 in a row or combine one small part with other foods having similar characteristics, you must be feeling thirsty quickly shortly after that, but we at McDonald's also have delicious sweets! This drives additional sales as not everybody is dare to drink tap water directly from the faucets, and even me sometimes do not drink them if feeling the water source unhygienic. After all this is not an ethical issue, as food vendors have the absolute rights to seeling those foods for extereme flavouring, provided if the product itself meets food safety standards.

And in addition to providing satisfying meals, McDonald's actively uses recycled materials for their outer packaging which allows them to lower prices of the actual products customers eat and drink. This move must be challenging in the beginning as collecting feedback of the outcome of changing into another material requires mass volume of works, but the outcome gives the company long-lasting revenue-generating opportunities. This is also KFC needs to learn from in order to address its obscureness. For the sheets McDonald's use to pack burgers and rice balls, the thickness is about 3-4 times smaller than what KFC uses, based on yesterday's rice meal I received. A small number of customers may think of using reduced packaging materials disrespectful, but the adverse effects can be easily moderated by satisfying meals, services pleasing customers, and the amenities provided by the restaurant.

As I write this journal, yesterday I was also given fried chicken and rice in a KFC restaurant. Compared with McDonald's their chicken had more mild taste and I can confirm at least this one was low in sodium. The taste was unwell, possibly because of leftover foods, but I can imagine a fresh one having the same recipe also tasting not good compared with those of McDonald's. They use their narrative of "top secret" for their products, but customers take care of direct feedback of taste, so that McDonald's will surely be a winner in this rivalry. And for their rice, it was just like mixing soup cooked with chicken with cooked rice or cooking them altogether, while after all it tastes like a plain meal with a little chicken bits, while failing to draw good senses of eaters to a perfect level; compared with McDonald's coconut rice, it gives a unique taste with the purity of coconut water and rice, plus some condiments adding additional tastes which had achieved a prefect level.

While KFC in Malaysia uses ketchup sachets not even bearing their own brand, the consistency of McDonald's products across different countries definitely grows loyal customers regardless of inhabitation and international travelling. In Kuala Lumpur I witnessed many Chinese tourists still calling McDonald's in their own way, "Mai Dang Lao" in Chinese just like what they do in their hone country; while the KFC art illustrations still exists around the world, inconsistencies would definitely make the memories of generations of people fading until oblivion.

III. Conclusion of Periods of Studies

As I became a guest of McDonald's, I also had learned so many about this company. It's success had once again proved that, a business dedicating to only one particular field of study wouldn't survive as this interconnected world requires people full of knowledge to this world.

Concluding the writing of this journal, I also appreciate myself for choosing not to continue attending schools in China, as this allowed ample time for me to researching and knowing more about this world. My journey of being homeless is not the start of an endless nightmare, instead this period of studies must had given me more knowledge about today's running world, for which it would then help me driving my business success in the future!

Thinking of whether McDonald's in Malaysia is a friend or adversary of mine, I can't give a clear answer, but I will definitely visit it in the future, eating their high-quality rice mixed with sauce, and possibly, access their Internet and charge my devices.