Written on 31/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Care from A Family Member (24 Oct 2025)
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

24 October 2025

===================================

When I finished exploring the new restaurant I planned to linger there for electricity and Internet access, just as I left it I received a phone call from my parent. It was my mom, and I talked about my recent activities and statuses.

My mom said on the call that, I need to fine-tune my moods as she worried that long time of staying in Malaysia (possibly with my current situation being homeless and waiting for formalities of my immigration status as currently being an overstayer) might generate mental health issues. I assured her that I was living happily there and I will work actively to ensure a good mental health condition and to rectify the problems of my identity.

She also told me of the proposed plan to having my dad visit me. I really miss her so much, so that I suggested she coming here for not only visiting me, but also getting in touch with the outside world. My opinion was, because the Chinese Communist Party brainwashes people with different, comprehensive ways knowing how good countries like Malaysia became hard for people like her as because the ideology had been already heavily manipulated and reshaped.

Hearing of my suggestions, she said that it will be later discussed as it was just an initial plan. We did not talk further about this.

As I gave assurance to her that I will invigorate myself, the call was later concluded and I went on to moving away from that restaurant for another place, possibly for preparation of sleeping to which I no longer remember.