Written on 20/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Suspicious Happening Observed (19/10/2025)
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

19th October 2025

===================================

I. Background

As I was accessing the Internet in Cyberjaya, Selangor, Malaysia, at a usual place I used to be able to connect to a WiFi network giving me Internet access, after around 2 hours of harmony time sometime at 6pm, I observed a man walking in the direction towards me, and immediaately started to secretly yielding at him while keeping body posture like nothing had noticed. After he walked behind me I noticed he raised his smartphone and faced the camera towards my body, so I immediately stood up and asked what he would going to do. His response clearly looked like my reaction was unexpected and he did either not trained well to conceal his identity, if his job entails investigation, or he's simply a public civilian. He started to say songthing I don't understand, but it was clear that the pronounciation is unclear, like some people panicking in fairness of something. He then started to step up towards me, possibly to robbing my laptop used for Internet access, and I quickly locked the Windows desktop and responded to keep a safe distance. His attempts was not succeed.

After that he walked away. I later saw a person behaving suspiciously looking back at that place of happening, located in an external area of a nearby building for which its first floor was used by an apparent restaurant outlet, based on an advertising board of it and the interiors which can be seen through the window.

II. Analysis, Security Assessments and Notable Details

An analysis was immediately started. It is concluded that he might come from the local city council or is a civilian who wishes to report an incident about me to authorities.

Security assessments later concluded on 20/10/2025 showed that this place is no longer safe, however the nearby bus station which was previously being used to charging devices still remains safe for use, provided that my presence is not known to the building behind it.

It's notable that during that time when I use my computer, I went to a nearby place surrounded by plants for [REDACTED] multiple times, and I also [REDACTED] often if ever [REDACTED]. I also went behind the bus station, in case I was charging devices before, for [REDACTED] for which the location might be partially visible to the said restaurant.

However, based on the reaction of that man, it's believed that he thought me suspicious of using a laotop at that location for a long time, or probably, for a long time and for many times, if he knew the frequency. It's also notable that on 20/10/2025 further assessment concludes that his appearance suggested that he had defeats which affects his intelligence resulting in the inability of logic thinking which furtherly affects his ability of recognising things in a way with reasonable intelligence.

Despite this observation, however, it's still unknown as of the time of writing this document (20/10/2025), his identity and the nature of his behaviour.

It's also notable that before this event had happened nothing suspicious were observed, however prior security assessments concluded that it's advisable not to use that nearby bus station for charging as to prevent possible police actions under possible public complaints, since I came and lingered here very frequently in recent months. On that day, I was not being in the bus station at all.

III. Outcome

This prompted me for an immediate plan of finding new places for WiFi access in order to get Internet. On 20/10/2025 as I think of past experiences, I made clear that most public complaints or believed public complaints against me do come with prior symptoms before a further enforcement action or confrontation might happen.