Written on 30/9/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Starting to Use the Tent Again
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

28th September 2025

===================================

PREFACE

Before I was moving to Kuala Lumpur on 26th September 2025, I knew that its safety situation won't allow me to not keeping a tent so that I could use at anytime. So, I decided to picking up the tent on mobility with me again. I still remembered that the last time I was using a tent for sleeping -- it was in Indonesia where I relied on this tent to give me the sense of safety. When I finally walked to the Sanur Beach from the Ngurah Rai airport in Bali, I relied on this tent to give me a little bit sense of safety; and when I found another place close to the airport and the McDonald's restaturant where I used to access the Internet while staying inside for which it gives little attraction from people nearby, I also used the tent to make a temporary sanctuary. On the day while I was departing from Indonesia, I slept at the airport and starting from that time, I haven't been using it for more than 3 months.

It was so heavy when I started to taking the tent with me again. Shortly after returned from Indonesia I stashed some parts of the tent -- those of most heavy -- at somewhere obscure and I haven't been seeing it until when I was about to taking it again. On 25th September before the day I started to leave, I picked up the tent to ensure that I'm still able to carry such a heavy thing with me on the go.

Kuala Lumpur is home to many homeless people, but I'd prefer to living in other cities for safety reasons. I would love to keep the places I often move around in Cyberjaya, especially that park I often used to sleep at night, still become "friendly" to me -- that said, I disappear for a certain period of time so that no people would see me "commuting" each day especially for coming to the park every night, which might result in complaints if someone in the know considers me a security threat or due to other reasons, and return after enough time has spent. As I planned to travel to nearby cities or take the train for long distance travelling, Kuala Lumpur was the ultimate choice. With the hope that I would be able to find places safely for sleeping without a tent, I moved to this city on the 26th.

II. Picking Up the Old Habit Again

The first night was generally fine, despite I was being harrassed by a man I changed place later and slept until the morning. However, on the second day I found someone suspicious -- with an unclear imaage I could see, after I woke up in the night, that a man, was facing towards the bench I was laying on, for an unknown reason. When I made signals telling him that I was awake, he moved slowly wiggling his body left and right as he stepped away. I was unsure what did he want to do, but I went on to sleeping since I had sense that he was unlikely to do something dangerous on me. As I was lying while becoming cautious, later I heard very light sounds. I knew that could be because someone was coming here but I didn't think of any signs to attack me, however I sensed burnt cigarettes in the air. I knew that some people was doing rogue things and I started to packing my stuff for moving -- a responsse I had already thought of under this kind of situation. It was someone with relatively small head size not consistent with this age wearing a hat -- I knew that this person must be uncivilised and exhibits rogue behaviour.

As the place I was using on the previous day was no longer considered, so I decided to choosing a place with the "on demand" approach again -- for which I initially used to decide which place to set up tent in based on the observations of environment when on the move to choose a safe and ideal place. Finally I chose to settle at somewhere under an escalated bridge. Before installing the tent I also found a man living in there already, and he waved his hands after found me. I thought he was a good man, and considering this, I decided to sleep together with him which will also give me encourages. He was that kind of person that despite not having a handsome appearance, his behaviour does not exhibit uncivilisation and rogue, and his kindness for which I could see from his behaviour, gave me such encourage as I knew that with him nearby, there would probably not having people daring to attack us, and even if someone does, he would be more or less defend this space.

I entered the tent while not having it covered by its dark-colour topping wafer. In fact, what I was worrying about was that [REDACTED -- WITH BASIC PROTECTION LEVEL] which will make it hard to escape, however with him being nearby I had actually got senses of safety. I went into sleep thereafter.

III. Results

It was a peaceful time despite with huge noise from vehicles nearby. I knew that he was not harrassing me. As daytime comes, I later packed everything and left the area.

During use of the tent, I kept the door opened to some degree to allow quick escape in the event of [REDACTED -- WITH BASIC PROTECTION LEVEL]]. In fact I did not want to use tent as this also gives me unventiliated air which makes me feel bad.
