Written on 14/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

TITLE:--

Short Summary on the Onwards Exploration of New Locations, October 2025
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

October 2025

===================================

CONTENTS

Shortly after the discovery of the new sanctuary -- the space of an escalated bridge and the nearby McDonald's restaurant both north of the Cyberjaya region, I went back to Cyberjaya again, for buying bodywears. My shoes are already broken so I need a new pair of shoes of course, and possibly I need to buy T-shirts as I have only one with good shape. Additionally, the zipper of my bags carrying belongings valuable to me such as laptops and tablets, have begun to fail so that I need to buy padlocks in order to eliminate the nuisance of zippers.

After buying everything necessary, with everything prepared, I began to leave again to finding new sanctuary, as the McDonald's in  this new sanctuary doesn't have a suitable area for using laptops and charging devices.

Around or on the day of 9th October 2025, I left Cyberjaya and planned to find new McDonald's restaurants with spaces similar to those escalated bridges where I can get relatively closed areas for living. I first went to the 16 Sierra region again, and later, I found a new McDonald's outlet on 11th October. It's notable that I spent the night connecting 10th October and the next day on a gradual ground placed with stones as I slept at a place surrounded by stones -- this is to deter people who wish to intrude this area. I laid down with heads being upwards just like using a chair, and with the protection of my sleeping bag it was generally fine keeping away from sharp objects and inconveniences caused by the non-flatness ground made with arrays of stones.

On the 11th, I found a McDonald's restaurant which can be considered relatively obsecure. It was outdated with some amenities not being updated in necessity, for example I saw a facility with an opening which allows placing newspapers with a message incicating that customers can pick up Malaysian newspapers The Sun for their "reading pleasure", but it was clearly to be outdated in the context of the current practice. Additionally, a poster with designs from the early to mid-term 2010s was found with copyright notice indicating a year between 2016 and 2019 (for which it's no longer remembered as of the time writing this journal). It had 3 floors available to guests, and I stayed on the 3rd floor using their Internet for hours. No shuffle music was played despite having speakers visible, and the outlet was surrounded by other buildings with crossings that can't be considered broad; this is the typical design found in Bali, Indonesia during my visit this June even in relatively developed places. It immediately gave me the sense of Indonesia, and this sense was also prominently signified by the scene while walking on a larger road which connects a smaller road to this restaurant.

While I planned to visit this restaurant in the future and make detailed capture of the scenes, with documentation of the geographical position, I later went on to find other sanctuaries. On the next 2 days, I was unable to find a suitable place and in the late night of the 13th, I went back to the escalated bridge at 16 Sierra and slepted thereafter.