Written on 26/10/2025 Malaysia Time
===================================

Exploring New Locations (20/10/2025 Onwards)
A SERIES OF MR. LI AO's ASYLUM-SEEKING JOURNAL

Not before 20th October 2025 to 25th October 2025

===================================

I. Background

On 19/10/2025 while I was staying somewhere I considered public place (no signs of indicating private properties), I observed a man suspiciously putting his smartphone towards me, and it prompted me for an immediate plan to changing place for charging my portable devices and to accessing the Internet. In particular, I have already planned not to using a nearby bus stop for staying to charge devices earlier, as to ensure that I can use it in a future time by making people "forget" about me so they think that I was only using it for a short period of time despite it may look so frequently.

So, after having everything prepared, I embarked on my trip again!

II. Starting to Using Tent in Jungle Places

On 21st October, while I was about to approach a McDonald's restaurant I found earlier as it was obscure and I lingered in a place charging my laptop while accessing the Internet without having any issues and did not observe any suspiciousness on the staff, I realised that if I buy foods and use computer I would be having only few hours since night is approaching. So I changed my route and approached a place as seen on Google Maps an escalated bridge with relatively safe spaces for sleeping. However, on the way I suddenly noticed that there was ample spaces for sleeping with tent while I could also keep myself hidden at a high place. So I decided to sleeping inside the tent again! At around 7pm I was already inside the tent, so I captured a video recording this moments.

Before doing this, I had a security helmet for motorcyclists on hands -- I captured it while walking on the road, possibly it was discarded by somebody. Using such kind of helmets was long being a plan to enhancing security for using a tent, as this would protect my head from sudden crush such as kicks from outside the tent so that I could keep safe. Despite these places I choose to sleep in a tent are always choosen with careful security considerations, employing a helmet adds an additional layer of protection.

I forgot if I was wearing that helmet all the time during sleep, but with sense of safety throughout the night, I went into sleep and had a peaceful night.

III. A Horrible Dream

During the sleep, I made a horrible dream. In the dream, I cleared immigration control at an airport using automated gates with my status as an overstayer in Malaysia, and it surpringly went through. I then departed for Thailand, but was refused entry and was repatriated into China. After I enter China, as I exited Shenzhen Bao'an International Airport and was on a road I used to be after exiting through a metro entrance, I was feeling like prevoous times after I entered China, but this time I felt hopeless -- on the one hand, I need to think of different kinds of government actions and to eliminate possible harm to me, and on the other hand despite my passport is not cancelled by Chinese authorities being a Chinese national there is really few places I can go visa-free, and since I overstayed in Malaysia and did not get a clearance Malaysia might refuse my entry so that I would be stranded at the airport again if I go there.

Although my worries were based on concrete facts about China, one thing is different in the dream -- I did not sense any cigarette smoke on my nose, wherever I was inside the airport or had exited to reach the outside. This completely contradicts the facts, as under influence of the Chinese Communist Party even smoking indoors can be tolerated while massive spread of smoking is given impunity by the government. Shortly after noticing that, I woke up and a moments after, I realised that I was still in Malaysia inside my tent. It was sometime between 3 to 6 am for which I did not remember, and I laid down after that. Relief spread in my mind after I clearly realised that I was still in Malaysia.

IV. Onwards Travel

On the next day I went to that McDonald's again using Internet for hours, and before getting dark at around 4-6pm I left the restaurant for the next destination, another McDonald's north of it. I was aiming to finding one for which I saw when travelling on a MRT train as I found its surroundings safe to navigate around, so possibly I may be able to find another one-stop sanctuary, from a safe sleeping place to a McDonald's outlet able to charging devices and using the Internet for long period of time at a relatively confortable location. That night while walking on the road named Jalan UPM I found it quite dangerous, as no service roads were given so that I would walk carefully outside the isolating line as cars passed over to me very near. Worrying about craters if I walk on the grass field, I set up my tent again at a jungle place by going deeper from the grass road attaching vehicle roads. Of course I knew that this place shouldn't be having craters, but shortly after I was inside the tent I heard sounds apparently from a broadcasting system of bell ringing. I checked electronic maps, and my location was just tens of meters away from a road I guess it was on the domain of UPM! But I knew that security staff wouldn't be checking this place based on the surroundings I had observed, so I went on for sleeping. This time the helmet was still being used, of course.

On 23rd October I was finally getting close to another target restaurant! Walking near the border of Kuala Lumpur displayed on Google Maps, I saw the KL Tower for the first time! Just before that I was about to see if I could see any landmarks as distance to the city center displayed on the map should allow me to see this, and really is, now I knew the distance to it on a real feeling. As I was turning over a road to the restaurant, I found the KLIA Ekspres train passing by, and felt really proud of me for my capabilities: although this time I relied heavily on electronic maps, this was due to safety reasons as dense population with diversified ethnicity surely will come with more dogs, and using such technology also helps me to finding the location of destinations since the road signs in Malaysia usually don't give detailed navigation information. But it's true that I was able to keep me safe and ensured a zero traffic accident happened on me!

I did not furtherly enter Kuala Lumpur, instead I slept in tent again at a jungle place. The rain was so heavy and my tent was also wet because of penetrated water. Fortunately my laptop was still able to be powered on after 3 times of failure, on the next day. I did not observed any moisture through the gaps on its rear case, but there might be a tiny amount of moisture which caused it to fail when I powered it on for the initial 3 times. Feeling confidence about my protection measure, despite my body got wet by the heavy rain throughout the day and night, and during the day my whole body went wet while all clothes and my shoes were also filled with moist, I knew how the rain had most likely affected this thing. I pressed the power button for another time, and this time, it finally powered on and entered the OS -- my protection measure worked. I was able to protect my laptop and tablet even as I was carrying a bag of them with visible holes running under the rain of moderate to heavy degrees.

After finishing tasks as I powered on my laptop, I went on and arrived at the McDonald's [REDACTED -- restaurant name removed] restaurant on the map. It was late afternoon so I requested plain water be refilled into my bottle, while during this time I observed the situation of the restaurant. It looked fine, so I decided to visit it again on the next day while spending a longer time using my devices, however, on the next day I wasn't be able to stay in there as the staff seemed to not be willing to having me. A woman referenced to my bags taken into the restaurant area, possibly blaming it for spreading smelly odors. My sleeping bag was in contact with my urine while being put inside the tent during that rainy night, and of course it was caused by the terribly-made tent, as urine poured or spilled outside the tent near around would eventually come back inside through openings of the bottom cloth. I vowed again that I won't be considering tents from Decathlon again until the company is proven to making products [REDACTED] practices, and I also vowed to [REDACTED] as I was hurt by [REDACTED] from this company as they made the tent hard to set up, so that I spent even minutes just for getting the upper water-proof topping cloth attached to the tent's body. It is still unsure if there was really a complaint from customer on that day because of the bad odor, as that woman mentioned "complaint", as I observed another suspiciousness which will be addressed in a separate document.

In the afternoon of 25th October 2025, I left the restaurant and decided to go back to Cyberjaya or the 16 Sierra region as the zipper of the tent which could use to stop moisquitos from coming in had became entirely unusable, and also because I was almost ran out of money so I need to save energy and eat less. Amid anger I removed the zipper by streching it, so I planned to first moving back to either the regions to ensure sleeping not to having problems, while I can also have relatively undistrubed time and spaces to analyse the tent to see if I can fix it by using other ways to seal its door so that I could continue using it while fully eliminating the zipper a big nuisance.

At about 9pm, I returned to the escalated bridge, and logged on to the platform being as my sanctuary. As I was approaching the destination, I really found this private space my home to some degrees. I went into deep sleeping after that.


