!!WARNING: Redacted version in this document.!!
!!	The original document is classified in order to 
!!	protect the asylum-seeking journey of Li Ao for a relative smooth process.!!
!!	It is scheduled to be released once such classified information!!
!!	no longer becomes confidential.!!

ASYLUM SEEKING JOURNAL OF LI AO
ON THE GIVINGS AND COURTESIES RECEIVED
November 2025
======================================

3/11/2025 (Malaysia Time):

	Staff at a KFC restaurant which is located near [REDACTED -- protecting the location trails of Li Ao] provided an additional drink, a lemon tea-flavoured with ice, in addition to the plain water I had requested.

	I thank the staff for kindness.

4/11/2025 (Malaysia Time):

	When I was requesting plain water at a KFC restaurant which is located [REDACTED -- protecting the location trails of Li Ao], the staff did not collect my water bottle. Instead they gave me a brand new bottle filled with water.

	I thank the staff for the kindness, especially that woman who previously gave me fried chicken and rice for her positive moods which made me happy.

5/11/2025 (Malaysia Time):

	When I was walking from my rest place [REDACTED - rest place location concealed for safety reasons] to McDonald's [REDACTED - name of McDonald's restaurant redacted for protection of Li Ao's location trails] for which I planned to access the Internet plus buying foods for eating, a man stopped his motocycle ahead of me while I was oppositing the driving position of the road. He gave me 5 Malaysian Ringgit. He was having look like those traditional Malaysian people in his 50s to 60s of age.

	Based on what he had said, I knew that he is kindful. I thank his courtesy as this improved my catering despite for only a single time. I used this money to buy a bottle of Fanta at inflated price beyond RM2.5 and below RM3, and a bottle of drinking water at RM1.5. The remaining money was then be used to buy a Digi reload code together with other money collected from other sources, including from pck-ups on the road.

	It's worth taking note that he mentioned "you guy" during our short talk for which the full sentence is no longer remembered. From his reaction I knew that he embraces different kinds of people instead of becoming conservative and refusing to acknowledge the facts of evolutions from the ever-changing world.