ASYLUM SEEKING JOURNALS OF LI AO
ON THE GIVINGS AND COURTESIES RECEIVED
October 2025
======================================

4/10/2025 (Malaysia Time):

	When I was walking from the 16 Sierrra area in Sepang, Selangor, on a road designed for motorised vehicle use, a woman driving a motorcycle stopped in front of me. She stopped me by making sound, and later gave me a bank note of 5 Malaysian Ringgit, making postures illustrating eating. Despite she was not speaking English, I thanked her in ENglish for her kindness and accepted the money. I later used this money to buy breads, of each priced at RM1.5 in total of 4.

	Her giving allowed me to buy more foods and had therefore improved my conditions on eating, despite it's not consistent.