ASYLUM SEEKING JOURNALS OF LI AO
ON THE GIVINGS AND COURTESIES RECEIVED
September 2025
======================================

20/9/2025 (Malaysia Time):

	1. In the afternoon at a 99 Speedmart shop in Cyberjaya, Malaysia, I was being told by shop's staff that someone had paid for all the goods I was about to pay after picking them up. This includes the following:

		-- A carbonated flavoured drink, sold at RM2.50 according to the label, with UPC code 9556404057153.

		-- A Pepsi coke drink, sold at RM2.50 according to the label, with UPC code 9556404001156.

		-- 7 numbers of packed pre-processed noodles, sold at RM1.80 according to the label, with UPC code 9555034809132.

	2. While I was moving ahead after leaving the shop, on the road to a bus station where I used to charge very often, I was given by a woman a plastic bag of food contained in a plastic bowl. She called me but not using English or any language I recognise, and wanted to hand me over a plastic bag, later put it directly into by bag. I thanked her for her courtesy despite non-intelligibilities with a smile. Almost immediately the given item felt onto the ground, she looked like going to help me, but I picked it up and placed into my bag. The woman was not wearing head cloth for coverying her body like those Muslims, and I guess she was coming from another country as a foreign worker. Regretfully, when I was going to eat stuff plus checking what she gave me, the contents had already spilled -- processed soybean like Chinese tofu, with a spoon, and a broken bowl. I ate some while disposed the rest mainly for safety reason while it might give me laxative effects but it tasted with sweet and nothing wrong were discovered.

	I felt sorry about not being able to taking care of this courtesy.
